#### Mr. Jagdish Belapure

Sr. Site Reliability Engineer | Certified AWS Solution Architect Associate | Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) | Google Cloud Certified Associate Engineer | HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate

Contact: 8698464149 | Email: jagdishbelapure@gmail.com

#### Summary:

Jagdish is an IT professional with 15+ years of experience in IT industry, having nearly 8+ years of experience in Cloud administration with a focus on Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Google Cloud Platform (GCP), and possesses good understanding of Microsoft Azure offerings. Besides provided DevOps solutions using tools such as Git, GitLab, AzureDevOps, Ansible, Maven, SonarQube, Terraform, Kubernetes – EKS, GKE and AKS, Datadog, Splunk .. etc.

- Experience in designing highly available, scalable, fault tolerant, cost-effective application infrastructure on premise and in different cloud providers like AWS, Google Cloud and Microsoft Azure
- Lead the design, architecture and implementation of AWS and GCP based infrastructure projects.
- Collaborate with IT, development and operations team to integrate cloud strategies and architecture.
- Specialized knowledge in DevOps tools, CI/CD pipeline using GitLab and AzureDevOps config management tools, artifact repository, Terraform, Containerization tool like Docker, orchestrations tool (K8S), Blue Green Deployment.
- Worked to layout Disaster Recovery plan for the applications, extensively worked on backup, restore of different services and components in Google Cloud, AWS, and Azure Cloud, also worked on Disaster Recovery (DR) activities.
- Extensively worked on deployment/release of the cloud-based products using multiple pipelines, also worked on taking backup using IBM Velero tool, Backup for GKE and few other internal tools to ensure reliability of the backups.
- Successfully migrated services and applications from legacy infrastructure/on-prem to AWS using various AWS services.
- Exposure in setting up Transit Gateways, VPC Peering, VPN and overall setting up secure cloud environment.
- Used various services from Azure like Microsoft Entra, Virtual machines, Azure Bastions, VM Scale set, Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS), Load Balancers, Virtual Networks (Vnet), Subnets, Azure CDN, Sentinel, Analytics Workspace, Application Gateway, Azure Monitors, Storage accounts, Azure SQL Database ..etc.
- Has exposure supporting Data Pipelines, which involves Data collection using Google Cloud Pub/Sub, Kafka,
  Data cleansing, Data processing, Data storage, analysis, and reporting. Used Google cloud services like Cloud
  Composer, Dataproc, Apache Beam, Flink, Dataflow, BigQuery, Logging & monitoring.
- Extensively worked on users and roles management, to ensure security of a cloud environment.
- Worked on collections of Logs, metrics to a central place from different cloud providers for analysis, incident management and reporting.
- Worked on analyzing vulnerability scan reports, prioritize vulnerabilities based on risk, and worked with security team to ensure timely remediation.
- SIEM management Develop and implement SIEM rules, alerts, and dashboards to detect and respond to security incidents, monitor security events, analyze logs, and correlate data to identify potential threats.
- Automated data extraction, transformation, and loading (ETL) processes using Python scripts and Pandas.
- Onboarding new tools like AppDynamics, Microservices, refactor existing tools & logging strategies, suggesting & implementing new architectural designs, automating use cases to reduce manual efforts.
- Specialized knowledge in Enterprise and System architecture Systems Integration, Infrastructure uplifts, database migration, Auth, LDAP and SSO implementation using OAuth 2.0, JWT, MFA.
- Experience in Web architecture, Security, Web server hardening, Apache httpd configuration, Load balancers, Firewall, Certificates, SSL, TLS, Akamai, DNS procurement & management.

#### Work Experience:

## Sr Site Reliability Engineer | Nokia | Bangalore, India | Jan 2023 to Present | Customer: Multiple Telecom Customers

- Experience in designing highly available, scalable, fault tolerant, cost-effective application infrastructure on premise and in cloud.
- Experience in Cloud Infrastructure, Infrastructure as a service, Cloud Operations and Build activities.
- Having exposure supporting Data Pipelines, which involves Data collection using Cloud Pub-sub, Kafka, Data preparation cleansing, Data processing using Al and ML, Data storage, analysis, and reporting.
- Worked on cloud native services like Cloud Composer, Dataproc, Apache Beam, Flink, Dataflow, BigQuery and Google Logging & monitoring.
- Extensively worked to deploy, manage, observe, the workload on different Cloud platforms like AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud.
- Provisioning of the cluster and resources in these Cloud using Terraform with code hosted in Azure DevOps.
- Defining backup strategies for Cloud SQL, Kubernetes and ensure they are working flawless with tools like Valero, backup for GKE and using other cloud native backup solutions.
- Worked on integrating these cloud platforms with Datadog for logging, monitoring, and observability.
- Fixing security vulnerabilities in a Cloud infrastructure.
- Basic understanding of Flask, Django, FastAPI, HTML and CSS
- Worked in agile model, also, mentored, set clear career paths for team members to help them grow. And performed regular evaluations, shared, and gathered feedback.

### Infrastructure Specialist | Publicis Sapient | Bangalore, India | July 2019 to Jan 2023 | Customer: Goldman Sachs

- Created and maintained the Microservices using YAML scripting, to implement Infrastructure as a Code (IaC), over the private cloud virtual machines.
- Worked on migration of the legacy application to cloud infrastructure, and implemented it till production.
- Worked on the creation of a Blue-Green deployment model for the investment portfolio env.
- Fixed application vulnerabilities identified by Security team, worked on certificate renewals.
- Worked on automating the deployment of the legacy application using deployment tool and python scripts.
- Successfully setup AppDynamics, Splunk monitoring tool with Clustered environments and used extensively to collect the logs, search, analyze, and create dashboards.
- Experience providing technical expertise throughout the application life cycle including design, implementation, and delivery of scalable infrastructure.
- Involved in production triage/outage calls, to help troubleshoot, identify & fix the issues in prod.

# Cloud Engineer | Capgemini Technology | Navi Mumbai | Feb 2016 - Jun 2019 | Customer: MetLife

- Over the past few years Jagdish has gained good experience on implementing different AWS services from infrastructure side, also working experience on AIX, Linux, & windows OS platforms
- He has implemented solutions using AWS services like VPC, VPC peering, Subnets, Security groups, NACLs, Auto Scaling, ELB, Route53 and used RDS instances.
- Ability to create highly available, resilient and fault tolerant architecture in Amazon Cloud. With the help of IAM, created roles, users and groups and attached policies to provide optimal access to the resources.
- Worked on the DB of the Amazon RDS & carried functionalities for creating instances as per the requirements. Implemented Amazon RDS multi-AZ for automatic failover and HA at the DB tier.
- He has good working experience on setting up VPN, direct connect, transit gateways and DevOps tools offered by AWS

### PeopleSoft Administrator | Cognizant Technology | Pune | July 2009 - Jan 2016 | Customer

During his tenure with Cognizant, Jagdish had worked on various customer assignments in different domains as a PeopleSoft Administrator. He had utilized skillset working on various platforms, like Windows, Linux, AIX besides on DB's like Oracle 10g/11g and utilized different tools and applications.

#### Education and skills:

- Education: B. Tech. Computer Science and Eng, SGGSIE & Technology, Nanded, MH 2008
- Amazon Web Services: VPC, Subnet, EC2, RDS, Security Groups, ELB, Auto Scaling, SMS, DMS, SSM, Transit Gateway, VPC Peering, VPN Setup...etc.
- Google Cloud: GKE, VM Instances, Cloud Storage, VPC Networks, Subnets, Deployment Manager, Cloud logging & Monitoring, Dataproc, Dataflow, BigQuery, Pub/Sub, Load Balancers, Cloud DNS, DNS Delegation
- Azure Cloud: AKS, Azure Instances, AzureDevOps. Etc.
- Programming Languages: Python
- Data Analysis: Pandas, NumPy
- OS/Database: Linux, AIX, Unix, Windows, Oracle database 10g/11g, SQL Server, RDS
- Tools: Git, GitLab, Conduit, Nexus, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, Splunk, AppDynamics... etc.

## Awards and Recognitions:

- Capgemini 'Extra Mile' Annual award- year 2015
- Publicis Sapient 'Core Values Partnering for Client impact' year 2020
- Publicis Sapient 'Core Values Learning Mindset' year 2021
- Nokia Nokia Business Excellence Award 2024